[{"questionNumber":"1","questionBody":"<p>Transactions are recorded or posted to the ledger in line with</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>Accounting Concept</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>Source document</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>Double Entry Principle</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>Data collection</p>\n</p>","answer":"C","solution":"<p>Based on the&nbsp;principle&nbsp;of&nbsp;double-entry&nbsp;system, for every debit there is a corresponding credit for an equal amount of money and for every credit there is a corresponding debit for an equal amount of money. That is, for every transaction one account is debited for, the amount of transaction and the other account is also credited.&nbsp;</p>"},{"questionNumber":"2","questionBody":"<p>Show how the following transaction will be recorded applying the double entry principle:<br />\nRent ₦50,000 was paid by Mr. Roi to his landlord on 1st July, 20 &times; 7 by cheque.</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>Dr Rent A/c; Dr Bank A/c</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>Dr Bank A/c; Cr Rent A/c</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>Dr Rent A/c; Cr Bank A/c</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>Dr Rent A/c; Cr Mr. Roi</p>\n</p>","answer":"C","solution":"<p>In the double entry principle, income and credit expenses are debited. In the question, rent account will be debited with the sum of #500,000 (money has come in as rent, e.i income),and&nbsp;credit bank account. (money has gone out of mr Rio bank account via the cheque that was issued)...</p>"},{"questionNumber":"3","questionBody":"<p>A statement in a double entry system in which are recorded all the transactions of one specific class, which takes place during the period is called</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>Double entry system</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>Ledger</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>Cash Book</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>Petty Cash Book</p>\n</p>","answer":"B","solution":"<p>Ledger also refers to a separate record within the general&nbsp;ledger&nbsp;that is assigned to a specific asset, liability, equity item, revenue type, or expense type. Here are examples of&nbsp;ledger accounts&nbsp;are: Cash, Accounts&nbsp;receivable, etc</p>"},{"questionNumber":"4","questionBody":"<p>The advantage of double entry is that</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>it is easy to prepare the final account</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>it increase assets</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>has cash and bank column</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>It disburses cash</p>\n</p>","answer":"A","solution":"<p>&nbsp;</p>\n<p>&nbsp;</p>\n<p>&nbsp;</p>"},{"questionNumber":"5","questionBody":"<p>Accounts can be classified into</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>cash and credit transactions</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>cash and credit accounts</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>personal and private account</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>personal and impersonal account</p>\n</p>","answer":"D","solution":"<p>A&nbsp;personal account refers to thee type of account&nbsp;for use by an individual abd for that person&#39;s own needs.&nbsp;</p>\n<p>Herr are soms&nbsp;examples&nbsp;of&nbsp;personal accounts:&nbsp;debtors, creditors, banks, outstanding/prepaid&nbsp;accounts,&nbsp;accounts&nbsp;of credit customers,&nbsp;accounts&nbsp;of goods suppliers, capital, drawings, etc.</p>\n<p>On the other hand, impersonal accounts are accounts which are not held in the name of the persons or are directly related to the customers or suppliers of a business</p>"},{"questionNumber":"6","questionBody":"<p>Goods were purchased for resale on credit costing ₦150,000 on 30th September 20X8 from Tosanwumi International. The entry to record these transaction is debit</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>Tosanwumi International, credit purchase Account</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>Purchase Account ₦150,000, credit Tosanwumi International Account ₦150,000</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>Credit Account ₦150,000, Credit Tosanwumi International ₦150,000</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>Tosanwumi International ₦150,000, credit credit Account ₦150,000</p>\n</p>","answer":"B","solution":"<p>We can assume that&nbsp;a credit purchase invoice was&nbsp;issued by the supplier, Tosanwumi International, which would be signed by Mr. Roi as evidence of his acceptance of liability to pay for the goods.</p>\n<p>Hence, the two accounts needed to record this transaction are purchase account and Tosanwumi&nbsp;Account. This involves having the purchase account debited while the&nbsp;Tosanwumi International Account credited.</p>"},{"questionNumber":"7","questionBody":"<p>If only wages is shown on the trial balance, it should be charged to the</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>profit and loss account</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>trading account</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>balance sheet</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>wages account</p>\n</p>","answer":"A","solution":"<p>It is dafe to assume (ubless otherwise told) that wages should be charged in the trading account only if shown separately on the trial balance from salaries.</p>\n<p>The wage is a direct trading expense to be included in the trading account while salary is an Indirect/overhead expense to be included in the P &amp; L account</p>"},{"questionNumber":"8","questionBody":"<p><em>Use the following information to answer this question </em><br />\nThe following are the final accounts of a trading organisation Wazobi ventures, for the year ended 30th June, 19x8</p>\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\n<tbody>\n<tr>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>₦</td>\n<td>₦</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Sales<br />\nless: cost of goods sold</td>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>233,000<br />\n170,000</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>63,000</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>less: Overhead Expenses<br />\nAdmin expenses<br />\nSelling expenses<br />\nOther overhead expenses</td>\n<td><br />\n16,800<br />\n15,000<br />\n6,200</td>\n<td><br />\n<br />\n<br />\n&nbsp;</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Net profit</td>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>25,000</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<p>What is the Gross Profit on percentage of sale?</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>2.7%</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>0.27%</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>27.0%</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>29.8%</p>\n</p>","answer":"C","solution":"<p>Gross profit percentage on sales = gross profit&nbsp;&divide; sales x 100</p>\n<p>= (\frac{63,000}{233,000}) x 100 = 27%</p>\n<p>&nbsp;</p>\n<p>And. 27%</p>"},{"questionNumber":"9","questionBody":"<p><em>Use the following information to answer this question </em><br />\nThe following are the final accounts of a trading organisation Wazobi ventures, for the year ended 30th June, 19x8</p>\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\n<tbody>\n<tr>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>₦</td>\n<td>₦</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Sales<br />\nless: cost of goods sold</td>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>233,000<br />\n170,000</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>63,000</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>less: Overhead Expenses<br />\nAdmin expenses<br />\nSelling expenses<br />\nOther overhead expenses</td>\n<td><br />\n16,800<br />\n15,000<br />\n6,200</td>\n<td><br />\n<br />\n<br />\n&nbsp;</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Net profit</td>\n<td>&nbsp;</td>\n<td>25,000</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<p>Calculate the net profit on percentage of expenses.</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>60%</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>25%</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>13%</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>65.7%</p>\n</p>","answer":"D","solution":"<p>Net profit on percentage of expenses =</p>\n<p><ins>Net profit&nbsp; </ins>&nbsp; x 100<br />\nExpenses</p>\n<p>= (\frac{25000}{38000}) x 100</p>\n<p>= 65.7%</p>\n<p>Ans = 65.7%</p>"},{"questionNumber":"10","questionBody":"<p>Mr Ojo gives you the following information on 31st July 2017<br />\nOpening Stock &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 7,000<br />\nClosing Stock &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 12,000<br />\nPurchases &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 60,000<br />\nExpenses &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 4,500<br />\nUniform margin of 33 (\frac{1}{3}) %<br />\nYou are required to calculate the sales</p>\n</p>","A":"<p>#55,000</p>\n</p>","B":"<p>#82,500</p>\n</p>","C":"<p>#27,500</p>\n</p>","D":"<p>#50,000</p>\n</p>","answer":"B","solution":"<p>Step 1: Convert the margin to mark-up:<br />\n33 (\frac{1}{3})%</p>\n<p>= (\frac{100}{300}={1}{3-1}={1}{2}) or 50%</p>\n<p>Step 2: cost of goods sold = opening stock + purchases - closing stock<br />\nC.p = 7,000 + 60,000 - 12,000<br />\nC.p = ₦55,000<br />\n<br />\nStep 3: prrofit = 50% &times; 55,000 = ₦27,500</p>\n<p>Hence,<br />\nSales = Cp + P<br />\n= 55,000 + 27,500</p>\n<p>= ₦82,500</p>"}]